(The tassel crowns the knight.
The sword is snow white.)
(In the silver saddle,
he rides like a shooting star.)
(He kills a man within ten steps.
Invincible he is all the way ahead.)
(He would leave once it's done.
No trace of him is to be found.)
=Sword Snow Stride= (Season 1)
=Episode 14=
Where are Ning Emei
and his Fengzi Battalion?
One li behind us.
[♪li: unit of length, equals 500 meters.]
When they're so far away,
how can they protect you?
We have Senior, don't we?
Xu Fengnian is quite scheming.
He has transferred Fengzi Battalion away
because he expects assassins.
When you use your martial arts,
he'll know who you are?
Clever girl.
But he's got the wrong plan.
Fengnian, I'll only keep you alive.
Even if all your subordinates
are killed,
I won't care.
Fengnian should be
out of Yongzhou, right?
Upon their traveling speed,
he should be.
Out of Yongzhou,
they'll be arriving in Qingzhou.
Lord of Jing'an in Qingzhou
is always at loggerheads with us.
I'm afraid
His Highness will
have some mishaps there.
Chu Lushan.
Here.
Don't go to the capital city with me.
But I promised His Highness.
How many days does it take
when you travel light to Qingzhou?
Two days only.
Oh.
You...
Stay by the gate of my mansion.
Once you receive the sword tassel
carried by the hawk,
lead your cavalry
to Qingzhou immediately.
Godfather, you want me
to invade Qingzhou?
No, or we would be rebelling.
Then what should I do in Qingzhou?
Fengnian will tell you.
What about you?
Many people in the capital city
want me to be dead.
But once I'm there,
no one dares to kill me.
Instead, they'll do everything possible
to keep me alive.
Do you know why?
With North Liang Army around,
you can live without any anxiety!
Here I go.
Godfather.
What?
Who'll lead North Liang Army?
No one can guard North Liang,
but Chen Zhibao.
(Liang)
Hawk.
Sword tassel.
Go fetch my bed.
I'll be waiting here
for the sword tassel.
I'm talking to you.
Go move my bed here.
Yes.
Quickly!
Armor.
Fujiang Armor?
Grandpa Wei, you know him?
When I was as young as you,
in this world,
there used to be four Great Masters.
One of them
was Fujiang Armor
from the South.
The man ahead of us?
But...
When Fujiang Armor
assassinated the late emperor,
Cruel Cat Han Diaosi
took off the Armor personally.
His dead body and the Armor
were hung on the flag for display.
It can't be faked.
That's weird.
Where did he get this armor?
Can he be the child
of Fujiang Armor?
No way.
There's only one Fujiang Armor
in this world.
Now,
the Armor should be kept
in the Imperial Palace.
Let me try him out.
You don't need to take the risk.
Shu Xiu.
Lyu Qiantang.
May I borrow your horse?
As you wish.
Which one of us should go first?
Shouldn't we go in turn?
He's alive.
Luckily,
he's not Fujiang Armor Man
among four Great Masters.
Who told you that?
Fujiang Armor
should have been stronger.
The Armor is from Mount Longhu.
It's ancient armor.
But few people know
that it can be divided into five armors,
referring to five elements.
Metal, wood, water, fire, and earth?
This is the Water Armor.
It's the strongest in the heavy rain.
They can't defeat him.
Ask them to get out of the way.
Stop.
Come back!
He's coming towards me.
It's over?
When Fujiang Armor is divided
into five bodies,
they aren't as strong as the entirety.
But they still can't be easily defeated.
He isn't dead yet?
A living death.
He's not exactly a living person.
Making Immortals Kneel.
Is he a human
or is he an immortal?
This old man is quite strong.
I'm afraid I can't defeat him.
It's really hard
to kill my brother-in-law.
I can't assassinate him directly.
I'll wait for another chance.
Luckily, I use the blade.
Otherwise,
when I saw how you used the sword,
I would have psychological scars
and never dare to use the sword again.
You don't use the blade
very well, either.
What do you think of that, girl?
Not as good as White Fox.
She's strong.
But far worse than me.
She uses two blades
much more beautifully.
I can use the sword beautifully, too.
She looks prettier than you.
Ah?
Seriously?
So, I won't be your disciple.
Think no more of it.
You are
as talented as Xu Fengnian.
If you learn from me,
you'll be a master.
Considering my identity,
the stronger I am,
the sooner I'll die.
You're afraid
that Xu Fengnian will kill you?
I don't think he wants that.
Bah.
He's sinister and ruthless.
He can do anything.
I can teach you.
Then you can defeat him.
I won't learn.
It's hard to learn martial arts.
Let me know when you want to learn.
Why must you teach me?
You're talented.
And you act arrogantly.
I like that.
What about him?
He has a good talent.
But he's scheming.
I'll keep observing him.
The two strokes
killed him.
But he looks alive.
The last breath, I'm afraid.
Dude,
who are you?
Why did you come to kill me?
Looks like he doesn't want to tell me.
It's not that
he doesn't want to tell you.
He just can't tell you.
Why?
I checked on him.
He's mentally disturbed.
Mentally disturbed?
But he was fighting normally.
Look.
It's carved
all over the inner side of the Armor.
What's it?
As for the secret pattern,
you have to ask that senior
in your carriage, I guess.
Look.
What's this?
A piece of armor.
What's carved on this side?
It looks mysterious.
I'm afraid no one knows it.
It's evil of you.
You're talking in riddles.
You know?
Tell us, then.
It's the genuine spirit.
Genuine spirit?
The pattern is carved
with special material,
for the circulation of genuine spirit.
Genuine spirit circulates
through the patterns?
More than that.
The patterns can also
store genuine spirit.
Most wonderfully,
the patterns can transmit
genuine spirit to this part.
Head?
So, the man out there
isn't born with superhuman strength.
Fujiang Armor is vicious.
A batch of death guards
have been trained.
Genuine spirit stored in the Armor
can help them to kill.
That's why I killed that man.
Because everybody in the Armor
would rather die than surrender.
(Unknown man)
It's all right that we buried him.
Why do we take away the Armor?
(Unknown man)
It's quite an evil armor.
(Unknown man) Let's study it.
He said there were five Fujiang Armors.
But only one came to kill me.
It's hard to say
if the other four would come.
Who told you only one came?
Three armors were waiting
in the woods just now.
Just now?
Yes.
Why didn't they come out?
They were scared of me, of course.
Wait.
Only four in total.
Where's the fifth one?
How do I know?
Oh, no!
Ning Emei.
Your Highness.
You were attacked?
Your Highness,
a man in Armor
attacked Fengzi Battalion.
What happened in the end?
I'm sorry.
More than forty soldiers
were wounded or dead.
But we failed to keep him.
We only drove him off.
In the end,
he ran away.
Please punish me, Your Highness.
I beg you
to spare the remaining soldiers
of Fengzi Battalion.
According to military rules
of North Liang Army,
how should generals and soldiers
be punished
for incompetence and failure?
Flogging is the least punishment.
Beheading is the harshest.
We ran into a man in Armor, too.
They two couldn't fight him.
You've already done a good job
when you drove him off.
Let me ask you.
During the fight,
did anyone of Fengzi Battalion
shrink back?
None of them ever shrank back.
Fengzi Battalion's men die in battle,
but they never run for their lives.
Good point.
When half of you were wounded or dead,
but you still fought bravely.
You're indeed valiant.
You fought bravely and won.
You're not guilty, but meritorious.
You may rise.
Thank you, Your Highness,
on behalf of Fengzi Battalion.
Take the remaining soldiers
back to North Liang.
Looks like
I'm going on a trip to destruction.
North Liang Cavalry
is never afraid of death.
Shouldn't dead soldiers be taken home?
Take them back to North Liang
and catch up with me.
I'll slow down and wait for you.
It was a nice trick to buy them over.
It's hard to judge Ning Emei.
But I think the other soldiers
would like to die for you.
It's not that easy
to buy over Fengzi Battalion.
I don't want them to die, either.
You're the son
of the Lord of North Liang.
It's justified that they die for you.
I take over North Liang,
just to eliminate such justified things.
You're a weird man.
Forget it.
Your sword moves were earthshaking.
I can't help asking who you are.
I use swords.
You can guess.
Don't bother.
He's Li Chungang.
(God of Sword Li Chungang)
How did you know?
God of Sword Li Chungang?
Sixty years ago,
God of Sword Li Chungang was famous
all over the world.
He used his sword Mumaniu
to fight everywhere
and no one defeated him.
I've heard about your sword.
I nearly forgot who I was.
Who else could remember Mumaniu?
So, you heard it.
Sixty years ago?
How old are you now?
Those who practice genuine spirit
live longer than those who don't.
With Dahuangting in your body,
you'll live longer than me.
Now that you're the former God of Sword,
where's your sword?
Jiang Ni!
What? It's taboo?
Nothing is taboo.
In the fight against Wang Xianzhi,
he broke my sword Mumaniu
with his two fingers.
He won?
My sword was even broken.
He certainly won.
Then you're going
to challenge Wang Xianzhi?
I just want to get back the sword box.
I don't have to challenge him.
You knew Xu Fengnian would
visit Wudi City?
I did.
Then why are you still going?
You think
I've been hiding underground
because I'm scared of Wang Xianzhi
for losing to him
and having my sword broken?
Isn't it the fact?
Losing a fight
never scares me.
I stayed hidden
only because
I realized that I was an idiot.
(Mount Qingcheng)
Your Highness,
if we choose
to make a detour,
it'll take us less than a day
to leave Yongzhou.
But if we go through
the back of the mountain,
I'm afraid it'll take a couple of days.
I know.
Your Highness,
is he
really Li Chungang?
Yes, I think.
What's wrong?
Why are you so excited
about his name?
He's God of Sword Li Chungang.
Masters appear one after another
in the martial world.
But he was the strongest
for fifty years.
His swordsmanship
was the best in the world.
He was the coolest swordsman
in the world, too.
Girls were crazy about him.
Other swordsmen admired him.
Shu Xiu,
are you crazy about him, too?
I grew up,
hearing a lot about his legends.
To me,
he's like the real god.
Qingniao, you don't look excited.
I'm a mere maid.
I love rich guys.
I'm not interested
in a poor old man.
Lin,
what about you?
Lyu Qiantang,
Lyu Qiantang!
I'm a scholar!
If he could be Number One Scholar,
I would admire him.
Boring man.
Let's hurry up.
We'll live in the Taoist temple tonight
where we can be sheltered.
Why do I feel the closer
we get to Mount Qingcheng,
the happier His Highness looks?
How do you know here's a Taoist temple?
I divined.
You're awesome, then.
Your Highness,
the Taoist temple
is a little bit weird.
How?
Trees in the backyard
have been cut down.
Oh.
They were used
to make a fire.
Make a fire?
I failed to find the firewood.
Then I cut down the trees.
So,
you came here, Your Highness?
Three years ago,
Old Huang and I lived here.
You once had a hard life.
Shu Xiu and Lyu Qiantang
went out for hunting.
Let's see
if they can take back some game meat.
It's good to have more people.
When Old Huang and I stayed here,
neither of us wanted to go out for food
even if we fainted from hunger.
Hey.
Come over.
Quick.
What?
What's this?
Let's knock them out.
Fengzi Battalion is away.
Tonight is the best chance.
Lyu Qiantang used to be a scholar.
Looks like he doesn't have
great martial arts.
Let's take him down first.
You know him a lot.
Have you heard me?
It's a deal, then.
You even found the white chickens
on Mount Qingcheng.
I'm getting a great feast.
I'm glad you like it.
Where's Lyu Qiantang?
Out there.
He said he would guard the carriage.
Ignore him.
He always pulls a long face.
How annoying!
Come on.
I want the drumstick.
Old Huang likes drumsticks, too.
Jian Jiuhuang?
I only know he's Old Huang.
He's gluttonous and lazy.
He's best at broiling sweet potatoes.
Come on.
Help yourself.
Why are you holding a stick?
To add fuel to the fire.
Ridiculous.
Your Highness,
how long did you stay here
with Old Huang three years ago?
For a few days.
Why...?
Why did you stay here?
We didn't stay.
We were caught by bandits.
Bandits on Mount Qingcheng?
Yeah.
They came, upon seeing the flare.
They didn't kill you?
They were stupid bandits.
Some were old and some were young.
When they saw starving Old Huang and me,
they gave us half of the roast chicken.
What good luck you had!
We became friends later.
When I left Mount Qingcheng,
they gave me a lot of food.
You came back here
because you wanted to see them again?
I missed them a lot.
If they see the flare,
they may come.
Give us your money!
A lot of people here.
- They're the stupid bandits?
- Take out your money.
Take it out.
- Not them.
- Give us your money.
- It's weird.
- Take it out.
This is supposed to be their territory.
Boss.
- Your Highness.
- Today,
- I'm experienced in the martial world.
- We'll get a lot.
Judged by my experience...
We'll be too busy.
There are two conditions
where former bandits have been replaced.
How dare you chat!
- You totally ignore me?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Take out your money!
- Take it out!
Girls come here!
First,
- the former bandits were expelled.
- As for men,
- What about the second?
- We'll kill them all.
They were all killed by new bandits.
As for girls,
we'll enjoy them all.
Holding a dagger, girl?
Sirs,
if I give this beautiful girl to you,
will you let us go?
We're dying, anyway.
May I ask you a question?
Where's Old Meng?
Cut the crap.
I'll kill you first.
Shu Xiu.
Your Highness.
Don't let anyone of them run away.
Try harder to fight me.
Fight her!
- Yes.
Don't rush to leave.
Come in and talk.
Spare me.
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
Please spare my life.
How long have you been
in Mount Qingcheng?
For more than a month.
In such a short time,
you haven't built your own camp,
have you?
The former bandits left the camp.
You killed them?
No, no.
But I know
they were in trouble.
Trouble?
What trouble?
Immortals of Qingyang Sect
took away a teenage girl.
Old Meng and his men
went to Qingyang Sect,
asking for the girl.
In the end,
none of them came back.
Xiaoque'er?
Why did they take her?
I heard immortals of Qingyang Sect
get stronger by hurting girls.
Maybe they just wanted that girl.
When was the girl taken away?
Before we came here.
Less than two months ago.
What else would you like to ask?
I've confessed everything.
How many people have you killed?
None.
We're poor men.
We didn't have a choice,
but to be bandits.
Grandpa Wei.
Here.
There's a slope a bit further south.
The camp is behind it.
Please go and check it for me.
All right.
Watch them carefully.
Don't worry, Your Highness.
None of them can run away.
Where are you going, Your Highness?
I'm going for walk.
I'll go with you.
This is
Yin-yang Pavilion.
It's said to be
the boundary of Mount Qingcheng.
It's the real world
at the foot of the mountain.
On the mountain,
it's the nether world.
It's hard to distinguish them, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's always hard to distinguish them
and it's hard to judge people.
Give me the writing brush and paper.
Keep still.
Your Highness,
it's quite dark.
How do you manage
to see the mountain so clearly?
I came to this pavilion before.
I've kept
the scenery in my mind.
Where are you going?
I've drunk too much water.
I'm afraid of the dark.
I need her to go with me.
Go.
What again?
When few people are around,
we can sneak away.
We've got nowhere to go.
Come on.
Don't waste time talking.
Go with me, anyway.
I'll take the cat with us.
Your Highness.
How did you find us?
I saw the flare
and I came to have a look.
How's the camp?
Many women were locked there.
They were kidnapped.
Their families were ruined.
Don't they want to take revenge?
They do.
But they're scared.
In the end,
they all left.
Will we send the bandits
to the government?
We're just kidding.
We're not running away.
We just...
Xu Xiao only asked me
to protect Xu Fengnian.
I don't interfere
with anyone else.
Off you go.
I won't stop you.
Let's go.
Quickly.
Don't bother.
North Liang
isn't far from here.
If I run away,
a message will be sent back
by a carrier pigeon.
You should at least try.
There isn't a chance.
Why do we bother?
Mm.
I...
I don't think you want to leave.
You can hear us?
I can whenever I want.
What do you think, girl?
Would you like
to learn martial arts from me?
With martial arts,
you can decide
whether you stay or leave.
I refuse.
According to His Highness,
the women are scared
after they've been hurt.
But it doesn't matter.
We'll take revenge
for them.
What does that mean?
The women in the camp...
You can't believe them.
They're cheap women!
We've got a lot of treasure.
I can give it to you,
as long as you let me go.
Dig holes.
(Villager Xiaoque'er)
Why can't I blow out a sound?
Let me teach you.
Oh.
Xu,
I knew you would leave.
I won't leave until I teach you.
All right?
Well,
come back and visit me later.
I will.
It's wise of you, Your Highness.
You've kept in mind the landform?
I shouldn't waste my trip.
They were killed.
Shu Xiu and Lyu Qiantang
buried them.
Mm.
What would you like to say?
Your Highness,
why didn't we send them
to the government?
The government may not kill
the criminals I give them.
The court always defends
the enemies of North Liang.
And of course,
they're mere bandits.
They're of little importance.
But just in case.
They've killed so many people.
I don't want them
to have any chance to stay alive.
Those bandits
deserve to be killed.
Not all bandits are so cruel.
When Old Meng was here,
he never killed people.
When he met poor men during the robbery,
he even gave them money.
He robbed Old Huang and me
when we didn't even have a single penny.
When we left,
he gave us a lot of money, instead.
He and his men were righteous bandits.
They weren't bandits.
They were just villagers
who couldn't make a living.
There were even the old and weak,
women and children among them.
There was a little girl,
named Xiaoque'er.
She kept asking me to teach her
to blow the leaves.
She often stole jerky
from Old Meng for me.
The girl
who was taken to Qingyang Sect?
Wu Lingsu of Qingyang Sect
was bestowed Lord of Qingcheng
by the late emperor.
He established Shenxiao Sect.
It's a sect in the martial world
as well as the spy for the royal family.
Mount Qingcheng is the first pass
outside North Liang.
Actually,
Wu Lingsu is spying
on North Liang in the dark.
I know.
I had planned
to avoid Qingyang Sect
when I had to pass Mount Qingcheng.
You did it right, Your Highness.
At present,
we're fighting for the inheritance
of the throne of North Liang.
We can't have a dispute with Wu Lingsu.
I promised Xiaoque'er
that I would come back for her.
She's been caught for two months.
It's too late now.
Yeah.
It's too late.
I can't save her.
Put it away.
To make a big difference,
one must be patient
and weigh up the pros and cons.
It's too late to save her, anyway.
I can
avenge her later.
But what if she's still alive?
Your Highness,
you should focus on our big plan.
Grandpa Wei,
I'm afraid I can't
make a big difference.
I'm going to break
into Mount Qingcheng.
♪ The flower of pain ♪
♪ Blooms in my heart ♪
♪ I made a bet with the dawn ♪
♪ That you'll answer ♪
♪ Forgive this tragic end ♪
♪ Moved by the moment we met ♪
♪ In spite of thunder and lightning ♪
♪ In spite of my falling ♪
♪ When we are apart ♪
♪ I'll collapse ♪
♪ Capture an image of the memory ♪
♪ After all these ups and downs ♪
♪ The vanity ♪
♪ Who will open it again ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ It's enough ♪
♪ Drowned in sadness ♪
♪ Just to see through ♪
♪ I will whisper love to you ♪
♪ For a lifetime ♪
♪ End the worry in the world ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ I'll be there for you all my life ♪
♪ After the moments of beauty ♪
♪ You are my reason to be ♪
♪ If there is a way ♪
♪ To start over ♪
♪ Will you still remember me ♪